<Document>
# Space Station 14

This entry marks the beginning of the advanced guidebook entries. Most information found here only applies to offical Wizard's Den servers, or servers that are similar to it.
Other servers may have their own guidebooks that you should read for relevant information.

If you're just here to play, that's great! The [color=#a4885c]Still new?[/color] section of this entry will help you out.

## Still new?
[textlink="Completely lost? Click here to start at the beginning." link="NewPlayer"]

[textlink="Don't know how to perform a job? Click here to jump to a list of departments." link="Jobs"]

[textlink="Keep dying? Click here to see a survival guide." link="Survival"]

## Navigation
Every station has a wide variety of locations to visit.
These range from specific departments where work happens to common areas where you can relax and chat with others.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StationMap"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignDirectionalDorms" Caption="Directional Signs"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignBridge" Caption="Marker Signs"/>
</Box>

[color=cyan]Station maps[/color] give you an overview of the entire station with colored markers denoting locations of different things.
Regular [color=cyan]signs[/color] on walls can point you to different departments.

## Leaving the Station
At the end of the shift [color=gray](barring a [color=red][bold]nuclear disaster[/bold][/color])[/color], you will leave the station via the [color=lime]evac shuttle[/color].
When it's called, an announcement will play on the station alerting the crew and signaling its [color=cyan]arrival in 10 minutes.[/color]
Once it arrives, you'll need to make your way over to it, board it, and then survive the trip to [bold]Central Command[/bold].

The round doesn't officially end until you reach [bold]Central Command[/bold]

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CryogenicSleepUnit"/>
</Box>

If you need to leave a round early, you can do so through a [color=lime]cryogenic sleep unit[/color].
Simply going inside and leaving the game will store your belongings and ensure that they are not stolen or misused.

## More Info
Learning the controls? [textlink="Click here to read about the different controls" link="Controls"]

Don't know how to perform a job? [textlink="Click here to jump to a list of departments" link="Jobs"]

Keep dying? [textlink="Click here to see a survival guide" link="Survival"]

Not all jobs or concepts will have guides yet, so if you're an experienced player we strongly encourage you to [color=#a4885c]contribute[/color]!
</Document>
