<Document>
## Dangers From Our Competitors
In our spinward stations, there exist threats from direct competitors to NanoTrasen. Conglomerates of companies, crime rings, and terrorist cells known for their unscrupulous practices, including the use of fear tactics, criminal methods, and corporate espionage to undermine and disrupt the operations of legitimate entities such as NanoTrasen. Their activities pose a significant danger to the safety, stability, and success of our stations and the company as a whole. Their motives range from obtaining valuable technology and proprietary information, to sabotaging critical systems, to directly attacking crew.

Identifying saboteur agents can prove challenging, as they often operate covertly and blend in with the station’s population. However, there are certain behaviours and indicators to be on the look-out for:

        [bold]Unusual Interest[/bold]

       - Individuals showing an excessive interest in sensitive research, proprietary data, or operational reasons without a legitimate reason may be potential corporate agents.

        [bold]Inconsistent Backgrounds[/bold]

       - Agents may provide inconsistent or fabricated personal or professional backgrounds, making it important to verify credentials through proper channels.

        [bold]Secrecy and Isolation[/bold]

       - Suspicious individuals may isolate themselves, avoid interactions, or engage with only select individuals or parties, raising concerns about their true intentions.

        [bold]Sudden Change in Behaviour[/bold]

       - Drastic changes in behaviour, such as displays of aggression or secrecy, could signal involvement with hostile groups.

[bold]To combat the presence of hostile entities, crew are advised to:[/bold]

    - Report suspected individuals.
    - Increase monitoring and patrols.
    - Identify unauthorised access attempts and potential breaches.
    - Secure critical data.
    - Conduct regular emergency drills.
    - Perform de-escalation training.
    - Implement advanced counter-espionage protocols.

Should any person or party aboard a NanoTrasen vessel be found to be currently affiliated with, or in the present employ of, any hostile company, crime ring, or terrorist group, they are to have their employment with NanoTrasen terminated where applicable, be stripped of any gratuitous access, and have any corporate property on their person or possession confiscated and returned to relevant station personnel. Such persons or parties may be heavily scrutinised by Station Security forces until they, or their remains, can be remanded to the custody of their employers, an independent port or vessel, or other local jurisdiction, at the earliest convenient time and at no expense to the company.

# Hostile Corporation Technology

Additionally, due to the presence of our competitors and their agents in the sectors in which our company operates, there is an ever-present possibility that hostile parties' technology or other property may manifest aboard our station by any number of means. The presence, acquisition, and distribution of such items should always be investigated and scrutinised heavily, and if Space Law and local legal ordinances allow, held securely, confiscated, and restricted from use.
</Document>
