<Document>
## Potential Threats
While working aboard NanoTrasen stations, you may encounter the highly unlikely scenario of your life being threatened by hostile forces. Fortunately, our highly-trained security teams are well-equipped to deal with such threats. Please note, however, that wasting company resources and time for a pre-emptive defense against a non-existent threat are grounds for demotion. Below are the potential hazards you may face:

[color=#999999][italic]NANOTRASEN DOES NOT TAKE RESPONSIBILITY FOR CREW INJURY OR DEATH IF CREW MEMBERS DISREGARD THE INFORMATION BELOW.[/italic][/color]

###Hostile Fauna

Be it from Epistemics experiments, corpses brought in by salvage, or something living in the vents, you may be attacked by hostile non-sophont entities. NanoTrasen does not encourage befriending such animals, unless it’s an approved experiment for research. Below are the procedures of how to deal with such a threat:

   - Do not engage with the threat yourself.
   - Evacuate the department or the zone.
    - Immediately inform Security of the incident. Provide details such as:
       - Threat type.
       - Estimated numbers.
       - Property damage.
       - Any additional information.
   - Inform Medical if there are injuries. If paramedics are unavailable, stabilize and carefully deliver the wounded to Medical.
   - Provide ID access if Security personnel are not able to enter the area.
   - Once Security confirms the threat being neutralized, clean up the department and report the incident to Command or Central Command.

###Hostile Boarding Parties

Due to the station’s invaluable resources and/or high profile crewmembers, NanoTrasen stations may attract hostile boarding parties. These individuals typically gain unauthorized access to the station and are usually armored, armed with deadly weapons. While their intentions are rarely known, common goals may include:

   - Assassination of crewmembers.
   - Theft of valuable station materials.
   - Theft of sensitive research.
   - Mass crew harm or terrorism.
   - Sedition of the chain of Command.
   - Detonation of the station’s nuclear warhead.

[bold]If such an unlikely scenario occurs, the following procedures are listed below:[/bold]

   - Do not engage with the threat yourself.
   - Seek immediate shelter.

    [bold]Immediately inform Security of the incident. Provide details such as:[/bold]
       - Hostile’s appearance.
       - What kind of armaments they’re equipped with.
       - Estimated numbers.
       - Last known location.
       - Property damage.
       - Any additional information.
    Inform Medical if there are injuries. If paramedics are unavailable, stabilize and treat the wounded. Only move the wounded if the path to Medical is safe. Do not take unnecessary risks.
    Remain in place until the situation has been resolved.

[bolditalic]In the case of overwhelming force that Security cannot handle:[/bolditalic]

   - Request assistance from Central Command through fax. In your fax, give as much detail of the threat as you can and the damages to the station and crew, alongside with signatures and stamps. Read “Contacting Central Command” for more information.
   - Evacuate the station.

###Unauthorized Cults

NanoTrasen recognizes and respects the free expression of religion aboard its stations. Discrimination of any kind will not be tolerated and is grounds for termination. However, Nanotrasen does not permit religious activity that involves:

   - Fanatical recruitment of additional members.
   - Harm to crew members, be it physical, psychological or metaphysical.
   - Practices associated with EarthGov banned religions that are officially designated as harmful cults.

For classification, speak with the station’s Mystagogue or Priest.

Please note that the Oracle’s religion is permitted aboard NanoTrasen stations, as they are the primary subject of research.

In the case of an unauthorized cult is suspected of forming on board, all crew members are encouraged to report unusual activity. Suspicious behaviour can be:

    Secrecy and Isolation. Suspicious individuals may engage only with selected individuals in secluded areas.
       - Sudden changes in behaviour. Known members having a sudden change in their behavior or personality may indicate their affiliation.
       - Otherworldly or physics defying effects occurring around certain crew members.
       - Appearance of unidentified anomalies.

[bolditalic]If a hostile cult is confirmed, follow these procedures:[/bolditalic]

   - Listen to Epistemics, Security and Command for any relevant information and orders about the threat.
   - Report suspicious individuals to Security and Epistemics. Give as much detail as possible, such as their appearance, potential tools, behaviour and more.
   - Form a group of trusted co-workers and stick together. Do not isolate yourself.
   - Await further instructions and remain in secure areas until the situation has been resolved by Security and Epistemics personnel.

###Pathogens

While all NanoTrasen personnel are vaccinated against a wide range of known diseases, and while the station's atmospheric systems utilize only the highest-grade filtration technology, an outbreak may still occur on the station. Most such incidents are minor in scope - like the common cold. However, employees are reminded to remain vigilant and to treat any outbreak with the seriousness it deserves.

[bold]In the event of a confirmed outbreak, please follow these procedures:[/bold]

   - Follow instructions. Listen to Medical staff and comply with all orders and updates.
   - Wear protective equipment, such as masks and gloves. Biosuits are recommended if available.
   - Maintain hygiene. Wash hands frequently, and clean up any potential biohazards.
   - Report Symptoms. Notify Medical and Security if any personnel display signs of infection.
   - Stay in your department.
   - Limit physical contact.

[bolditalic]If you’re starting to show symptoms of the pathogen, please immediately follow these procedures:[/bolditalic]

   - Immediately head to the Medical Department.
   - Inform Medical personnel of your symptoms.
   - Listen to all orders from Medical personnel.
   - Store any valuable NanoTrasen gear, weaponry or property in a secure location.
   - If a treatment is currently unavailable, quarantine yourself in Medical.
   - Await treatment.

###Unions

NanoTrasen supports free speech, the right to fair working conditions and does not consider itself anti-union. However, The Company is not neutral either. NanoTrasen will always defend the interests of its customers, shareholders and associates. Worker unions may disrupt work productivity, which can in turn jeopardize job security for all crew members.

If an organizing union attempts to use force to advance its goals, such as vandalizing Company property or physically attacking other crewmembers, Security is authorized under Space Law to quell and suppress unions.

It is every crew member's duty to report potential warning signs of unionization to their managers. Warnings signs may be:

   - Crew members refusing to work.
   - Usage of union related terminology, (living wage, working conditions, etc.)
   - Circulation or distribution of petitions and union fliers.
   - Unusual interest in Company policies, benefits, employee list or any other Company information.
   - Noticeable changes in behavior among known crew members.
   - Non-manifest individuals supporting union activity.
   - Clothing, accessories associated with unions.
   - Increased negativity and complaints.

[bolditalic]In the case of a violent union riot, follow these procedures:[/bolditalic]

   - Do not join the riot.
   - Inform Security and Command immediately. Provide details:
       - Names and job positions of any suspected union members and leaders.
       - Whether the union members are armed.
   - Inform Central Command of the incident.
   - Shelter in a safe place and await for the situation to be resolved.
   </Document>
