<Document>
  # Definitions
  The terms specified below are defined for further use within the procedures.
  - Captain: The officer legally appointed by Nanotrasen as Commanding Officer of the station. This title is only transferable by Central Command.
  - Commanding Officer / CO: An officer appointed to lead the station and its Command department, whether it be the Captain by Nanotrasen, or an Acting CO by Station Command.
  - Command Staff/Station Command: Members of the Command department who lead a department aboard the station.
  - Crew: All sophonts employed by Station Command, or by NT to reside on the station and perform an established function therein. This includes any sophont listed on the Crew Manifest or issued a functional NT identification and access card. Individuals imprisoned by NT, along with those imprisoned during the course of a shift for violations of Space Law, are considered Crew.
  - Judge: An individual legally appointed to preside over a hearing, as specified within [textlink="Hearing Procedure" link="HearingProcedure"].
  - Detainee: Any sophont whose free movement has been curtailed by law enforcement on suspicion of criminal activity. They have not, however, been officially charged with a crime.
  - Arrestee: Any sophont who has been formally charged with a crime.
  - Prisoner: Any sophont who has been sentenced for the commission of a crime, or awaiting a hearing for a capital offense.
  - Permanent Brig/Permabrig/Brig: A secure location for the long-term confinement of Prisoners. Typically outfitted to sustain the basic survival needs of the Prisoners within.

  # Entity Definitions

The following definitions are provided to clarify the legal protections- and obligations- that Standard Operating Procedures and Space Law provide to any given entity. Unless explicitly covered by a more distinctive term, all Entities are to be treated as such until clarification is provided.
Entity

Any individual with a distinct existence. Entities may also encompass a plurality of identities contained within a single physical form. NanoTrasen does not require Entities be offered the protections of Standard Operating Procedure, Space Law, or Rules of Engagement unless further defined below. Security Officers are encouraged to be reasonable with their use of force regarding circumstances, especially if Entity's termination would leave lawsuits or tarnish reputation for NanoTrasen.
Pet

Any Entity that is provided to NanoTrasen Space Stations- either through the station's Logistics Department, or brought on board by the crew- for the purposes of emotional support. Any harm against such a Pet may render the offender liable to the crime of Animal Cruelty. Examples of Pets include, but are not limited to:

      -  Renault the Fox
      -  Smile the Rainbow Slime
      -  Laika the Guard Dog
      -  Silvia the Medical Cobra
      -  a corgi, purchased by Station Logistics
      -  hand-held "personal AI" devices

# Synthetic

Any Entity consisting primarily of non-organic matter, designed and/or constructed by NanoTrasen or its Employees for the purpose of performing tasks aboard a Space Station. Synthetics are bound by software limitations, typically referred to as Synthetic or Silicon Laws, and physically incorporated into their chassis. Any damage to a Synthetic- including un-authorized modification of their Laws- may leave the offender liable to charges of Sabotage. Irrevocable destruction of a Synthetic may leave the offender liable to the crime of Grand Sabotage. Examples of Synthetics include, but are not limited to:

       - Crew-constructed Cyborgs
       - The Station AI
       - Positronic Brains

# Employee

Any Entity who has a contract with NanoTrasen. Typically, these individuals possess all of the following:

       - A communications headset (or similar communications capability) outfitted with encryption keys relevant to their assigned job function.
       - An ID card with their name and job function, pre-programmed with door access relevant to aforementioned job function.
       - Company-approved attire for an individual of their job function.

In situations where an individual lacks one or more of these items, law enforcement officials are encouraged to use their best judgement, and mitigate any risk of liability to charges of Endangerment or Abuse of Power. Harm or death of an Employee may leave the offender liable to the crimes of Assault, Manslaughter, or even Murder. Examples of Employees include, but are not limited to:

       - All crew present on the Space Station, including those who are removed from cryogenic stasis during the course of a shift.
       - Any crewmate arriving from a different NanoTrasen Space Station, due to navigation errors, disasters, or similar.
       - Individuals imprisoned by NT, along with those imprisoned during the course of a shift for violations of Space Law.
       - Any and all members of NanoTrasen Central Command, including Emergency Response Team soldiers and Central Commanders.

In cases where there is reasonable doubt as to the identity of a member of Central Command, the Commanding Officer is encouraged to request clarity from Central Command themselves.

Any Employees that are fired by Station Command are still considered Employees until Central Command can confirm their contract termination.

# Provisional Employees

Provisional Employees are a special subcategory of Employee. During the course of a shift, events may lead to an Entity, or Entities, arriving aboard the station who wish to be employed by NanoTrasen. The Head of Personnel, alongside any relevant departmental head, may accept the Entity into NanoTrasen's employ provisionally.

In such a case, the Head of Personnel must create a document listing the Provisional Employee's name and assigned job function, along with any physical features deemed necessary to identify them. This must be signed and stamped (where applicable) by the Head of Personnel, their relevant departmental head, and the Provisional Employee. A copy must be kept within the Head of Personnel's records, and with the Provisional Employee if possible.

Provisional Employees serve "at will", and may have their employment revoked at any time by Central or Station Command authorities.

</Document>
