<Document>
# Crimes Code Quick Reference

Crime codes are organized into four Category Codes (_XX) as listed below, with the most severe crimes being given the highest Severity Codes (x__). The sentencing officer or Judge should use discretion, and not charge an entity with two similar crimes for a singular offense.

For example, an attack upon an Employee which causes them to die of their injuries is Murder, not Assault AND Murder. Likewise, an entity should not be charged for both Possession AND Grand Possession on a singular Controlled Item held without proper authorization.


  # 1XX - Misdemeanor

  For minor crimes, fix the issue then warn the person to not attempt the crime again, if they still proceed to do it at a later date, a brig time may be better.

  ## Animal Cruelty (Code : 101)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To inflict unnecessary suffering on a sapient being with malicious intent.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 5:00



  ## Harassment (Code : 102)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To verbally demean, humiliate, or harass an entity with malice; or maliciously spread false information amongst a population.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 5:00


  ## Vigilantism (Code : 103)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To perform the responsibility and duty of a law enforcement official without approval or due cause to act.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 4:00

  ## Petty Larceny

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To deprive an entity of an item in their lawful property without consent.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 4:00


  ## Tresspass (Code : 105)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To enter into an area where one is not authorised nor invited.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 3:00


  ## Vandalism (Code : 106)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To deface or superficially damage public property, or property belonging to another person.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 3:00

  ## Hooliganism (Code : 107)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To intentionally and maliciously engage in disruptive conduct, where one refuses to cease.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] As necessary.



  # 2XX - Felony

  ## Assault (Code : 201)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To cause physical harm or to effect unwanted physical contact on an Employee, without the apparent intent to kill them, or to threaten such actions with both capability and intent to do so.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 10:00


  ## Breaking and Entering (Code : 202)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To break and enter into a high security area where one is not authorised nor invited, with intent to commit a crime within.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 10:00

  ## Rioting (Code : 203)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To partake in an unauthorised riotous, tumultuous, and disruptive public assembly that refuses to disperse after warning.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 8:00


  ## Endangerment (Code : 204)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To recklessly abandon obligations involving the continued wellbeing and/or protection of life and property, through malpractice, action, or inaction.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 8:00


  ## Posession (Code : 205)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To be in unauthorised possession of restricted items or items of particular danger. See Controlled Substances/Items, Controlled Armaments.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 5:00 - 10:00

  ## Obstruction of Justice (Code : 206)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To wilfully disobey, interfere with, or refuse a decree of the court, warrant, or arrest.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 8:00


  ## Perjury or False Report (Code : 207)

  [bold]Description[/bold]:	To wilfully and maliciously tell an untruth either in court or in the process of making an actionable report to law enforcement.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 6:00

  ## Contempt of Court (Code : 208)

  [bold]Description[/bold]:	To conduct oneself disruptively and disrespectfully before the court.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 6:00

  ## Identity Theft (Code : 209)

  [bold]Description[/bold]:	To maliciously assume the identity of an entity, such as through writing, attire, and/or speech.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 5:00


  # 3XX - Grand Felonies

  ## Manslaughter (Code : 301)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To act without malice in a manner which, directly or indirectly, leads to the death of an Employee.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 16:00


  ## Kidnapping (Code : 302)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To unlawfully confine or restrict the free movement of an entity against its will.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 16:00

  ## Grand Possession (Code : 303)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To be in the possession of a Category C, D, or E Controlled Armament.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 15:00 - 25:00

  ## Noöspheric Tampering (Code : 304)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To maliciously tamper with or create noöspheric anomalies, entities, aberrations, or other elements; Or to otherwise deliberately perform actions that would raise Glimmer or other anomalous reading levels in a way that threatens normative reality.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 14:00

  ## Sabotage (Code : 305)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To maliciously commit an act that, directly or indirectly, hinders the operation of a vessel of its part; or, to commit an act that modifies and/or damages technology or equipment one is not authorized to access.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 14:00

  ## Abuse of Power (Code : 306)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To intentionally misuse or wrongfully exercise one’s own authority, influence, or control, resulting in harm, unjust treatment, or demonstratable loss to another entity.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 14:00

  ## Grand Larceny (Code : 307)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To deprive an entity of any Controlled Item in their lawful possession.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 12:00

  ## Black Marketeering (Code : 308)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To sell, distribute, or otherwise circulate Controlled Items to unauthorized entities.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] 12:00



  # 4XX - Captial Crimes

  ## Murder (Code : 401)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To maliciously commit an act resulting in the death of an Employee, with reckless indifference to their life.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] Capital Punishment

  ## Terrorism (Code : 402)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To maliciously commit an act or take hostages with reckless indifference to life in order to provoke a state of terror in, intimidate, or otherwise compel an entity to act or abstain from acting.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] Capital Punishment

  ## Grand Sabotage (Code : 403)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To maliciously commit an act that, directly or indirectly, renders a vessel or its part uninhabitable or inoperable; or, to commit an act that causes irreversible damage to High Security Areas and/or systems of a vessel.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] Capital Punishment


 ## Prevention of Revival (Code : 404)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To commit an act that prevents the revival of an Employee by standard medical care following their death.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] Capital Punishment

 ## Sedition (Code : 405)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To act to overthrow a lawfully established Chain of Command or governing body without lawful or legitimate cause.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] Capital Punishment

## Breach of Custody (Code : 406)

  [bold]Description[/bold]: To escape the custody of law enforcement while serving a legal sentence, or awaiting trial for a capital offense.

  [bold]Brig Time Issued:[/bold] Capital Punishment
</Document>
