<Document>
  # Space Law
  Space Law is a [bold]broad set of rules and regulations[/bold], collected and regulated by TerraGov, enacted and enforced by NanoTrasen and its Station Security, with the oversight of CentCom - and, on occasion, TerraGov's Galactic Police Force. Space Law applies to all ranks and positions on stations under its jurisdiction, from the lowliest Passenger to the highest Captain; all are equal under the eyes of the Law, and all must ultimately answer to it.

It is highly recommended to read the Standard Operating Procedures. Summaries of several pertinent sections are listed below.

   - [bold]Controlled Items[/bold]: If a member of station crew requires access to a Controlled Item for use in their job, or for regular function, they must obtain the signed and stamped approval of a relevant member of Station Command or the CO. The latter is able to override the decisions of Station Command in this regard, however.
   - [bold]Entity[/bold]: Any thing with distinct, independent existence.
   - [bold]Employee[/bold]: An entity who has an employment contract with a Company.
   - [bold]Security Jurisdiction[/bold]: Station law enforcement officers are bound by Space Law; they cannot operate outside of standard accessible areas, or perform searches, unless such action is allowed by either Alert Procedure or a valid warrant.
   - [bold]Detainment & Arrest[/bold]: Members of law enforcement may detain entities under Probable Cause of criminal activity. These detainees must be informed of the crime they are suspected of committing, and may be moved to a secure location and/or restrained while law enforcement determine if a crime was committed. Such detention should last no longer than five minutes. Any entity may be arrested, during which they are restrained, informed of their charges, and taken to the brig for search and processing under Brig Procedure.
   - [bold]Sentencing[/bold]: Any member of law enforcement is allowed to pass sentence on Misdemeanor, Felony, and Grand Felony charges. The Chief Justice, or in their absence, the Head of Security are allowed to pass sentence on all Charges.
   - [bold]Treatment of Prisoners[/bold]: Prisoners must be provided with food, water, clothing, free movement within the brig, adequate medical care, access to the Common and Prison radio channels, and moral, spiritual, or legal counseling if requested and available. If the brig becomes uninhabitable, prisoners must be securely and safely relocated to another area until the brig is functional once more. Prisoners sentenced to Extended Confinement have additional rights and firmer restrictions that must be upheld by law enforcement officials.
   - [bold]Paroles & Pardons[/bold]: Parole may be offered under the discretion of the Warden, Head of Security, or CO. A parole hearing requires only a Judge, as discussed within Trial Procedure. Pardons may be issued by the arresting officer, the Judge of a trial, by the Warden (to those within the permanent brig), or by the CO, when deemed in the best interest of the crew or vessel, or when the circumstances of the crime warrant suspension of sentence.
   - [bold]Pressing Charges[/bold]: Any Employee may press charges against any other entity. Individuals may only be charged with a crime if it can be proveny beyond reasonable doubt that they have committed the crime.
   - [bold]Trial Procedure[/bold]: A criminal trial’s Judge must be, in sequential order: The Chief Justice, the Court Clerk, an impartial member of Justice or Station Command, or the Warden. The Prosecution should ideally be the Prosecutor, or an available member of Station Command or Station Security in that order. The Defense should ideally be a member of the Justice department assigned to the defendant, though they are allowed to represent themselves if they wish. If insufficient crew are available, the Judge is fully authorized and strongly encouraged to pass a sentence of Extended Confinement until a proper trial can be held.
   - [bold]Alert Procedure[/bold]: Codes Blue, Red, Gamma, and Delta authorize Security to carry progressively more advanced equipment, and loosen Rules of Engagement regarding their use. The former two codes disallow openly carrying firearms by non-Security personnel; the latter two suspend many rights to privacy, and grant Security the power to do whatever neccessary to retake or scuttle the station.

If a defendant is accused of a crime, they are granted the privilege to challenge the legitimacy of charges of claims brought against them. Any of the following may be invoked:

       - [bold]Double Jeopardy Clause[/bold]: accused persons may are not to be charged on the same charges following an acquittal or conviction, except in the case of acquittal and subsequent credible admission of guilt.
       - [bold]Entrapment Clause[/bold]: accused persons found to be induced or coerced into the commission of the crimes listed in the charges are to be acquitted.
       - [bold]Exclusionary Clause[/bold]: evidence collected and/or analyzed in violation of accused persons’ rights under law is inadmissible.
</Document>
