<Document>
  # Rule C3: Antagonist Guidelines
[color=#ffff00]Being an antagonist does not allow you to stop playing a character. Determine how your character would react to being given these objectives, and work through it appropriately.[/color]

Through engaging in antagonistic activity, you should seek to make the round more engaging and fun as the primary driver of the narrative of a round. Succeeding as an antagonist should not be your goal, but rather telling the most interesting story for everyone involved. 
  - [color=#ff0000]Antagonists are free to complete their objectives through committing proportional damage. Through roleplay, damage becomes more proportional.[/color] Example: Holding the singulo hostage for a theft objective is acceptable, while simply singuloosing and using that chaos is unacceptable. 
    - Killing players unrelated to your immediate objective in a manner that results in their round removal should be avoided. Crew that do not make an attempt at self preservation, or engage in valid-hunting, are exempt from this. 
    - If you are concerned as to whether or not what you're about to do is allowed, feel free to AHelp and ask an admin for clarification. [color=#ff0000]Lack of administrator response does not constitute approval.[/color]
  - While antagonists are [color=#ffff00]not required[/color] to complete their objectives, they are still encouraged to act as an antagonist in the round while roleplaying. 
  - Other antagonists are not necessarily your friends. Other antagonists are often free agents that you may negotiate with at your own risk. 
    - If you are a team antagonist, you must work with your partners to complete any shared objectives.
  - Excessively lame tactics are strictly forbidden for all antags except for station-destroying antags, such as nuclear operatives or space dragons. Examples include:
    - [color=#ff0000]Explosives and strategies with capacity for high collateral damage used on or around the evacuation shuttle[/color]
    - Heavily damaging/spacing or camping arrivals/cryo
    - Unnecessarily extending the round
    - Behavior that calls the round to an end prematurely
</Document>
