<Document>
  # Thaven

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobThaven" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! This species has a severely limiting game mechanic and is not recommended for new players.[/color]
  [color=#ffa500]This mechanic makes it very difficult to form a consistent character or personality, as it can severely affect the way a Thaven speaks and interacts with others.[/color]

## Moods
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PositronicBrain" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The Thaven have a unique brain structure, similar to a positronic brain, and thus have "Moods" which affect them similarly to a borg's Laws. [color=red]Breaking these moods is extremely distressing![/color] [color=#ffa500]As such, a Thaven must follow their moods to the best of their ability. The consequences of violating these moods is up to the player, but they should be very upset at any violations and seek to rectify them.[/color]

## Mood Swings
  Thaven brains are susceptible to fluctuations in noöspheric pressure. As a result, their ability to synchronize and regulate their Moods tends to degrade with extended exposure to the glimmer that builds up in NT research stations. [color=#ffa500]It also renders them vulnerable to glimmer discharges[/color], which can sometimes give them additional, often severely debilitating moods.

## Thaven Nerve Pinch
  Thaven hand-to-hand martial arts have a focus on inflicting non-permanent damage. As a result, [color=#ffa500]their unarmed attacks are slow, and deal no damage[/color], but [color=#1e90ff]cause a fair amount of stun buildup[/color].

## Damage
  Due to their relatively fragile bone structure and unique nervous system, they take [color=#ffa500]10% more damage from Blunt, Slash, Piercing, and Genetic sources[/color], as well as [color=#ffa500]20% more damage from Radiation[/color]. However, their aquatic ancestry allows them to take [color=#1e90ff]10% less Heat, Cold, and Poison damage[/color].

## Thaven Naming Conventions
  Thaven typically name themselves after a single virtue they hold dear. Sometimes these names can be long and unwieldy.

  For example:
  - Honesty
  - Have Mercy
  - Give Thanks To Thy Ancestors
  - Obedience
  - Search The Scriptures
</Document>
