  <Document>
# Server Rules
  This is a Delta-V server. You must be at least 18 years of age to play on this server. By connecting to this server, you agree to our privacy policy found at [color=#808080]https://discord.gg/deltav[/color]

    [color=#ffDD00]This is an [textlink="Auteur Roleplaying (ARP) server." link="DeltaVARP"] [/color] This means that we expect you to roleplay and engage in the round as a character at all times. Both Crew and Antagonists should be focused on authoring the narrative of the round. Players are given broad freedom to be creative, so long as they are roleplaying in good faith.

    All of our rules are written to align with our [textlink="Mission Statement" link="DeltaVMS"].
    Many rules are designed to require roleplay, and not all rules are intuitive. Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play so that you aren't surprised. Most of our rules will be met with a warning, followed by an appeal-only ban. Game admins will treat you as if you have read the rules, even if you have not.
    If you have any questions about these rules, please use the admin help menu by hitting F1 in-game or clicking the "AHelp" button in the lobby, or by making a post in the "Rules Clarification" forum at [color=#808080]https://discord.gg/deltav[/color]

    ## Community Rules
    These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.
  - [textlink="0. Admins can exercise discretion in the enforcement of rules." link="DeltaVRule0"]
  - [textlink="A1. No sexually explicit or erotic content." link="DeltaVRuleA1"]
  - [textlink="A2. Use English and be excellent to one another." link="DeltaVRuleA2"]
  - [textlink="A3. Do not share in-game information outside the game."" link="DeltaVRuleA3"]
  - [textlink="A4. Engage in proper AHelp and CHelp etiquette." link="DeltaVRuleA4"]
  - [textlink="A5. Do not exploit the game." link="DeltaVRuleA5"]

  ## Game Server Rules
  These rules apply within the context of rounds.
  - [textlink="B1. You must roleplay a character." link="DeltaVRule1"]
  - [textlink="B2. Use communication channels appropriately." link="DeltaVRule2"]
  - [textlink="B3. Use in character knowledge." link="DeltaVRule3"]
  - [textlink="B4. Follow reasonable escalation." link="DeltaVRule4"]
  - [textlink="B5. Leave the game using cryosleep." link="DeltaVRule5"]
  - [textlink="B5. Do not grief." link="DeltaVRule6"]


    ## Command, Security, Justice and Antagonist Guidelines
  These rules apply within rounds for specific roles.
  - [textlink="C1. Command, Security and Justice Guidelines" link="DeltaVRuleC1"]
  - [textlink="C2. Prisoner Guidelines." link="DeltaVRuleC2"]
  - [textlink="C3. Follow Antagonist Guidelines" link="DeltaVRuleC3"]

  ## Silicon Rules
  For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules. You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon.
  - [textlink="S1. Your silicon laws are rules" link="DeltaVRuleS1"]
  - [textlink="S2. Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="DeltaVRuleS2"]
  - [textlink="S3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="DeltaVRuleS3"]
  - [textlink="S4. You cannot request or allow a law change" link="DeltaVRuleS4"]
  - [textlink="S5. You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="DeltaVRuleS5"]
  - [textlink="S6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="DeltaVRuleS6"]
  - [textlink="S7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="DeltaVRuleS7"]
  - [textlink="S8. Crew are staff members; make reasonable assumptions" link="DeltaVRuleS8"]
  - [textlink="S9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="DeltaVRuleS9"]
  - [textlink="S10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="DeltaVRuleS10"]
</Document>
