  <Document>
# Server Rules
  This is a Delta-V server. If you are banned on this server, you will be banned on all Delta-v Servers. You must be at least 17 years of age to play on this server. By connecting to this server, you agree to our privacy policy found at [color=#808080]https://discord.gg/deltav[/color]

  [color=#ffDD00]This is a roleplaying (RP) server. Try to immerse yourself into your character. This includes interacting with your fellow crewmates, and using roleplay as the primary vessel to play the game alongside things like your job on the station. Roleplaying places less emphasis on "winning" and more on just telling a story.[/color]

  Space Station 14 is not like most games. Many rules are designed to require roleplay, and not all rules are intuitive. Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play so that you aren't surprised. Our community rules specifically are zero-tolerance rules, meaning that a violation will result in an appeal-only ban. Game admins will treat you as if you have read the rules, even if you have not. If you have any questions about these rules, please use the admin help menu by hitting F1 in-game or clicking the "AHelp" button in the lobby, or by making a post in the "Rules Clarification" forum at [color=#808080]https://discord.gg/deltav[/color]

  ## Community Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  - [textlink="0. Admins can exercise discretion in the enforcement of rules." link="DeltaVRule0"]
  - [textlink="A1. Do not say or do sexually explicit or erotic things." link="DeltaVRuleA1"]
  - [textlink="A2. Use English and be respectful." link="DeltaVRuleA2"]
  - [textlink="A3. Follow the rules regarding livestreaming current rounds." link="DeltaVRuleA3"]
  - [textlink="A4. Engage in proper AHelp etiquette." link="DeltaVRuleA4"]
  - [textlink="A5. Do not exploit the game." link="DeltaVRuleA5"]

  ## Game Server Rules
  These rules apply within the context of rounds.
  - [textlink="B1. Behave like a normal person." link="DeltaVRule1"]
  - [textlink="B2. Follow the Metashield." link="DeltaVRule2"]
  - [textlink="B3. Do not prioritize winning over roleplay." link="DeltaVRule3"]
  - [textlink="B4. Do not behave like an antagonist as a non-antagonist." link="DeltaVRule4"]
  - [textlink="B5. Leave the game using cryosleep." link="DeltaVRule5"]

  ## Command, Security, Justice and Antagonist Guidelines
  These rules apply within rounds for specific roles.
  - [textlink="C1. Command, Security and Justice Guidelines" link="DeltaVRuleC1"]
  - [textlink="C2. Prisoner Guidelines." link="DeltaVRuleC2"]
  - [textlink="C3. Follow Antagonist Guidelines" link="DeltaVRuleC3"]

  ## Silicon Rules
  For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules. You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. 
  - [textlink="S1. Your silicon laws are rules" link="DeltaVRuleS1"]
  - [textlink="S2. Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="DeltaVRuleS2"]
  - [textlink="S3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="DeltaVRuleS3"]
  - [textlink="S4. You cannot request or allow a law change" link="DeltaVRuleS4"]
  - [textlink="S5. You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="DeltaVRuleS5"]
  - [textlink="S6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="DeltaVRuleS6"]
  - [textlink="S7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="DeltaVRuleS7"]
  - [textlink="S8. Crew are staff members; make reasonable assumptions" link="DeltaVRuleS8"]
  - [textlink="S9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="DeltaVRuleS9"]
  - [textlink="S10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="DeltaVRuleS10"]
</Document>
