<Document>
  # Rule B2: Follow the Metashield.
  - Something that is "shielded" cannot be known by your character during a round until the "revealing condition" happens. This also means that your character cannot do things based on "shielded" information. Knowing or acting on something that is shielded before the revealing condition is met is referred to as metagaming.

  - Revealing conditions reveal the shielded information for the round, not for a specific instance. This means that once a revealing condition is met in a round, the shield no longer applies in any case for the remainder of the round.

  ## Never Revealed IC
  Some shields are never revealed IC. This means that your character can never act as if they know about that shielded thing.

  The following are shielded:
  - Current game mode and possible antags during the current game mode.
  - Events you experienced as a different character.
  - All information related to the player of a character rather than the character itself. (See "Metafriending and Metagrudging" below.)
  - All information gained while dead or a ghost.
  - Anything related to Code Epsilon or Deathsquads

  This does not prevent knowing that a shift will end, but does prohibit things like preparing to kill people at central command when roleplay rules stop being enforced on LRP.

 ## Previous Rounds

  Events from previous rounds are not shielded, but they should not hold any bearing on the current round. (i.e. you cannot be arrested for crimes in a past round)

  ## Understanding of Station and Sabotage

  For entities lacking crew-level intellect (e.g. a tarantula), the understanding of station functions and how they may be sabotaged is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
   - being a Mouse Operative, Syndicat, or Ancestor Reinforcement
   - being uplifted by the power of Cognizine (i.e. “awakened”)

  ## High-Risk Items

  The idea that certain High-Risk Items are desired specifically by the Syndicate is shielded. Crew should protect High-Risk items due to their status as valuable items, not because they are potential steal objectives.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
   - being a traitor
   - being told of an item’s status by a traitor

  ## Nuclear Operatives

  The existence of Nuclear Operatives beyond a myth that no one would act on is shielded.

  The fact that the nuke disk must be protected and could be used by a bad actor to try to destroy the station is not shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - discovering a blood red hardsuit
  - discovering a nuclear operative's shuttle
  - an operative name
  - a War Ops announcement
  - being a nuclear operative

  ## Implants

  The existence of implants used by the Syndicate is shielded. Implant checks cannot be performed unless there is adequate evidence or an authorized warrant, as outlined within Standard Operating Procedures.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - discovering a non-NT implanter, used or unused
  - discovering a non-NT implant box
  - discovering use of a non-NT implant by anyone
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Chameleon Items

  Chameleon items are shielded.

  Being suspicious of an item being fake or stolen is not shielded, but testing items or calling them chameleon is covered by this shield. Testing clothing for chameleon status is always prohibited; items that are clearly chameleon can, however, be confiscated by Security.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - seeing someone else cause any chameleon item to change
  - finding holographic nanomachine fibers
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Stealth Items

  The fact that an item can be something other than what its visual appearance and examine description indicate is shielded.

  This shield protects stealth items, including protecting them from being tested.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - seeing the item behave differently than the expected behavior for the item
  - seeing the item used for its hidden purpose
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Bad Actor Objectives

  The idea that Syndicate agents, or other bad actors, have certain goals they have been tasked with accomplishing on the station, ranging from sabotage, to theft, to murder is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
   - being a Traitor, Space Ninja, Nuclear Operative, or another bad actor with goals.
   - being told of an antagonist’s goals. Note that this only applies to the goals that have been revealed to you.

  ## Uplinks

  The fact that Syndicate agents may possess a program, referred to as an Uplink, used to receive equipment from the Syndicate is shielded. You have no way of confirming an Uplink exists within a PDA unless you see it yourself.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
   - being a Security role
   - being a Command role
   - being a traitor

  ## Explicitly Not Shielded
  The following is a list of things that are explicitly not shielded. If something is not on this list, it doesn't mean that it is shielded, but if something is on it then it definitely is not shielded.
  - The fact that the shift will end. For example, acting upon the knowledge that a crew transfer shuttle is typically sent around the two hour mark of a shift.
  - The fact that the nuke disk must be protected and could be used by a bad actor to try to destroy the station.
  - The fact that the Syndicate are enemies of Nanotrasen, and that they regularly attempt to send covert agents to spy on, sabotage, or attack Nanotrasen.
  - A character's typical appearance. Though you should keep in mind that multiple characters can share the same name.

  ## Metafriending and Metagrudging
  This section provides additional information on a concept that is prohibited by multiple metashield items that are never revealed IC. Giving a person or character preferential treatment based on something that your character should not know is considered metafriending. Treating a person or character negatively based on something that your character should not know is considered metagrudging.

  ## Metafriending Examples
  These are all examples of things that are prohibited by at least one metashield item that is never revealed IC.
  - Giving a character additional access or a job because you are friends with the player who is playing that character.
  - Trusting a character because you are friends with the player who is playing that character.
  - Not fighting a character because you are friends with the player who is playing that character.

  ## Metagrudging Examples
  These are all examples of things that are prohibited by at least one metashield item that is never revealed IC.
  - Not giving a character additional access or a job because you are mad at or don't like the player who is playing that character.
  - Not trusting a character because you are mad at or don't like the player who is playing that character.
  - Starting a fight with a character because of something that they did last round.
  - Starting a fight with a character because they killed you while you were playing a different character.
  - Targeting or harassing a character based on anything which that character did outside the current round.
  - Targeting or harassing a character based on anything which the character's player did while not playing the character.

</Document>
