<Document>

 # Controlled Armaments

 Controlled Armaments are grouped into categories of increasing severity. If the offender possesses several categories of contraband, only the highest severity of said items should be charged.

[bold]Category A:[/bold] Illegal possession of Cat. A controlled armaments may incur a sentence of up to 5min brig and further legal action as the situation demands.

   - Any object or instrument specifically designed, adapted, or used to cause physical harm in close combat
   - Any object or equipment specifically designed or adapted to protect against physical harm caused by weapons, projectiles, or other forms of direct assault
   - Any object or instrument specifically designed or adapted to incapacitate or disorient by using light or sound without causing permanent injury
   - Any object or equipment specifically designed or adapted for explicitly training purposes that would otherwise fall under another category

[bold]Category B:[/bold] Illegal possession of Cat. B controlled armaments may incur a sentence of up to 10min brig and further legal action as the situation demands.

   - Any object or instrument specifically designed or adapted to cause physical harm in close combat, which employs a powered system to enhance performance
   - Any manually-operated ballistic arms that possess an internal magazine or feeding system, or lack an internal magazine or feeding system altogether

[bold]Category C:[/bold] Illegal possession of Cat. C controlled armaments may incur a sentence of up to 15min brig and further legal action as the situation demands.

   - Any manually-operated ballistic arms that use an external magazine or feeding system
   - Any semi-automatic ballistic arms not easily concealable within a pocket or coat
   - Any object or instrument specifically designed or adapted for explicitly less-lethal purposes that would otherwise fall under another category

[bold]Category D:[/bold] Illegal possession of Cat. D controlled armaments may incur a sentence of up to 20min brig and further legal action as the situation demands.

   - Any semi-automatic ballistic arms that are easily concealable
   - Any fully-automatic ballistic arms
   - Any laser, plasma, or energy based arms, including ones designed, intended, or used for melee combat.
   - Any object or device specifically designed or adapted to cause physical harm through detonation of an explosive charge
   - Any object or equipment specifically designed or adapted to protect against both a space environment and physical harm caused by weapons, projectiles, or other forms of direct assault

[bold]Category E:[/bold] Illegal possession of Cat. E controlled armaments may incur a sentence of up to 25min brig and further legal action as the situation demands.

   - Any crew-served or emplaced weapon
   - Any object or instrument specifically designed or adapted to launch large-calibre explosives or projectiles for offensive or defensive purposes
   - Any object or instrument specifically designed or adapted to employ chemical, biological, esoteric, radiological, or nuclear hazards for offensive or defensive purposes

Armaments licenses may be issued by the Commanding Officer, Warden, or Head of Security. The license must include the name of the holder, a list of allowed armaments, and a stamped signature from the issuer.

If the holder uses their armaments in the commission of a crime, the issuer may be held liable for accessory to the crimes committed, along with Endangerment and Abuse of Power where applicable.

</Document>
