<Document>
# Psionics
[color=#a4885c]Psionics[/color] are mental abilities that interface with the [color=#a4885c]noösphere[/color]. Humans have limited access to the noösphere's full potential, allowing some to find ways to command it.
The abilities originate from distorting a noöspheric imprint into a specific shape, a bit like a lock and key. This means that humans can only have a single ability at a time.
An imprint shaped for metapsionics will not work for invisibility, and vice versa.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobIfritFamiliar" />
Many other creatures are much more in tune with it than humans, allowing them to access more powerful psionics like [color=#a4885c]kineses[/color].

## Telepathy
All psionic entities have a shared telepathic communication channel. It's anonymized, so you never know who you are talking to. Statistically, it probably is not human.

## Glimmer
[color=#a4885c]Glimmer[/color] is a more colloquial term for [color=#a4885c]noöspheric pressure[/color], measured in [color=#a4885c]milli-Psi (mΨ)[/color]. The noösphere can be considered analogous to an atmosphere. In a localized area, everything will equalize towards a certain pressure that's based off of the total energy in the system.
Note that unlike atmospheres, areas of noopsheric pressure do not operate by physical contigiousness, but mental. This means that areas with intertwined destinies will experience the same latent glimmer regardless of physical separation.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SophicScribe" />
The [color=#a4885c]sophic scribe[/color] tracks glimmer.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerProber"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerDrain"/>
</Box>

Epistemics can build devices to interact with glimmer. These are usually the main determiners of where glimmer is going.
[color=#a4885c]Glimmer probers[/color] will increase glimmer, but directly generate research points without further input. [color=#a4885c]Glimmer drains[/color] simply drain glimmer at the cost of electricity.

Use of psionics will increase glimmer, as will [color=#a4885c]noöspheric storms[/color].

## Discharges
Glimmer will occasionally discharge if it's above 100 mΨ, causing a wide range of effects based on just how high it is. The most common is giving all entities with psionic potential a small seizure,
which is something most people working on stations with an Epistemics department have grown used to.

## Acquiring Psionics
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Oracle" />

Psionics can be acquired in a number of ways. The oracle will sometimes dispense a strange liquid called [color=#a4885c]lotophagoi oil[/color], which at high glimmer levels is guaranteed to give psionics.

Random discharges may give you psionics as the seizure knocks your noöspheric imprint into just the right shape.

[color=#a4885c]Space drugs[/color] are an easier to acquire but much weaker alternative to lotophagoi oil.

## Psionic Insulation
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadTinfoil"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHelmetInsulated"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PillCryptobiolin" />
</Box>
[color=#a4885c]Insulative clothing[/color] and [color=#a4885c]cryptobiolin[/color] will render you immune to psionics, but prevent you from using any you have.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadCage" />
Security has a more forcible option for insulative clothing.

## Handling Glimmer Emergencies
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerProber"/>
Probers should be turned off before glimmer exceeds 500 mΨ.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GlimmerDrain"/>
Glimmer drains are quite effective at draining glimmer, taking it out as fast as a prober can put it in.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarNanotrasen" />
Sacrificing psychics will reduce glimmer instantly by a decent amount.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PillMindbreakerToxin" />
Metabolizing 20u or more of [color=#a4885c]mindbreaker[/color] will remove psionics from a person, meaning they will not generate any more glimmer.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShellSoulbreaker" />
[color=#a4885c]Soulbreaker[/color] shells will remove psionics from psychics they hit.

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ectoplasm" />
[color=#a4885c]Ectoplasm[/color], combined in a beaker with equal parts water, ash, blood, and plasma, will produce a normality crystal when heated enough. [color=#fcdf03]Use a hot plate for this.[/color]

</Document>
