<Document>
  # Controlled Substances

  Controlled substances are any substances that have been restricted or made illegal under space law. A noncomprehensive list of controlled substances is as follows:
  - Space Drugs and other hallucinogenic agents
  - Mindbreaker Toxin and other psionically restrictive agents
  - Corpium and other highly infectious or rapidly-acting chemical or biological agents
  - Desoxyephedrine and other stimulants
  - Nocturine and other sedatives
  - Explosive and pyrotechnic compounds
  - Toxins and poisonous compounds
  Any individual who requires any of the above items in the course of their job or for regular function may request access to a prescription or special dispensation from the [color=lightblue]CMO[/color], which will describe the controlled substance(s) being prescribed, the amount where applicable, and a certification of authority, such as a stamp or signature.

  ## Controlled Items
  Controlled items are items that have been restricted or made illegal for passenger possession and use. Additionally, any information, intelligence, or technology providing insight into the development, production, or procurement of a controlled item is also itself a controlled item. The current list of controlled items is as follows:
  Weapons and ballistic or reflective body armour (see Armament Licensing)
  - Cryptographic systems, software or technology
  - Nuclear materials, weapons, and technology
  - Long-range telecommunications and broadcast technology
  - Navigation and maritime guidance equipment or technology
  - Telecommunication and signal jamming technology
  - Hypodermic spray tools and refillable hypodermic auto-injectors
  - Cloaking, chameleon, and IFF-inhibiting technology
  Any individual who requires any of the above items in the course of their job or for regular function may request a document of authorisation which is to contain an itemised list of the approved information, intelligence, or technologies, the name and position of the holder, and a stamped statement of approval from the commanding officer; this document must be held secure by both parties. Should the holder of such a document commit crimes pertaining to the listed items, the authorising party may be found guilty of accessory to said crimes, in addition to endangerment and abuse of power where applicable.
</Document>
