<Document>
  # Jurisdiction

  Members of security and of command are fully authorised to withhold crew members at their discretion. The crew member ordered to answer to the authority is obligated to do so, regardless of whether they consider their orders lawful or not. Any grievances and suspicions of unlawful proceedings or mistreatment are to be directed up the Chain of Command and resolved judicially, ideally enlisting legal counsel if available.

  Any person that is suspected of having committed a crime may be detained. In detainment, the officer will inform the detainee of the crime they are suspected of committing. They may then be held on-site or moved to a more strategically sound location, possibly restrained at the officer’s discretion, and invariably detained for the time necessary for security officers to determine the circumstances of the incident and whether to effect an arrest or not. A detainee may or may not be searched prior to being either released or arrested.

  Any person that is charged with having committed a crime may be arrested. In the event of an arrest, the suspect will be restrained by an officer, informed of their charges, and taken to the security department for a search and processing. The charges may be pressed by a member of security or a head of department, or clearly outlined in an arrest warrant authorised and stamped by the commanding officer or head of station security. A lawyer or legal counsel may be requested by the arrestee and must be provided if available.

  Unauthorised departmental searches and raids constitute a violation of the law, unless explicitly outlined in a warrant issued and authorised by the commanding officer or head of station security; such a warrant may authorise entry into specified areas, by force if necessary, and may order the arrest of listed individuals implicated in a crime or crimes.

  Similarly, advanced surgical procedures, cursory implant inspections, and any other other invasive searches similarly constitute a violation of the law unless stipulated within an authorised warrant, or with both probable cause and evidence.

  Security personnel hold a nigh unrestricted armaments licence under T3, and are authorised at all times to use lethal force to the extent necessary to neutralise adversaries under any of the following circumstances:
  - If the adversary’s number or strength leave the officer at a severe tactical disadvantage.
  - If the adversary exhibits a clear and present danger to the vessel by physical means.
  - If the adversary poses a significant threat of serious bodily injury or death to the officer or others.
  - If the adversary presents an existential threat to the chain of command by illegal means.
  …wherein an “adversary” is an entity that demonstrates a hostile intent, commits or directly contributes to a hostile act that does not constitute an actual attack, or is actively attacking the vessel or its crew.
</Document>
