<Document>
  # Treatment of Prisoners

  Prisoners have certain rights that must be upheld by security and command personnel.

  Prisoners must be provided with the following:

  Adequate medical care and moral, spiritual, or legal counselling if it is requested and available.
  - Access to the common radio channel, and the common radio channel only. This right may be revoked should it be abused.
  - Clothing, food, and water on request.
  - Should the holding cells or permabrig become uninhabitable, prisoners must be securely and safely relocated to another area for confinement, until the holding cells or permabrig be returned to a serviceable state.
  - Prisoners should be granted freedom of movement within their holding area unless there is an undue risk to life and limb.
  - Additionally, prisoners in Extended Confinement have certain rights but also more firm restrictions that must be upheld by law enforcement:

  Visitation may be permitted only for prisoners sentenced to Extended Confinement. A maximum of one individual may be permitted to visit a single convict every 10 minutes; a reason must be provided for the visit, and the visitor must consent to a search of their belongings.
  - Prisoners who intentionally seek to, or succeed in, escape from their holding area are thereby guilty of a capital crime and may receive trial.
  - Prisoners who intentionally and maliciously cause structural damage to the permabrig, to a degree that makes it unreasonable to hold prisoners within, are thereby guilty of a capital crime and may receive trial.
  - Prisoners who intentionally, maliciously, and repeatedly cause significant bodily harm to their fellow inmates, visitors, and/or security staff are thereby guilty of a capital crime and may receive trial.
  - Prisoners may request retrial for capital crimes; these requests may be refused depending on the discretion and availability of the potential judge, or at the discretion of the warden or head of station security.
  - Prisoners may request or may otherwise be given parole without prompt by the warden, head of station security, or commanding officer (see Paroles and Pardons).
  - Should prisoners repeatedly and maliciously antagonise law enforcement, to an extent where continued extended confinement becomes infeasible, the warden is fully authorised and encouraged to temporarily upgrade the relevant prisoners’ sentences to Preservative Stasis summarily.
</Document>
