<Document>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RoboticArm" Caption="The factory must grow."/>

Using the Goobstation's Factorio system many machines and processes can be automated.

The first step is Epistemics department unlocking the [bold]Industrial Engineering[/bold] technology, which unlocks everything you need.

If you have played with Factorio or the Create mod you will be familiar with how it works.

## Robotic Arm

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RoboticArm"/>

This is the main workhorse for automation, it moves items from an input tile (or storage) to an output tile (or storage).

Without any configuration, it will work with items on the floor infront of it and behind it, moving them from one tile to the other.

[bold]Use a multitool[/bold] to link its input and output machine to [bold]automated machines[/bold].
Any signal port that starts with "Item:" is compatible and indicates a linkage of item transfering.

It also has a [italic]Moved Item[/italic] signal port which is activated after an item is moved to the output. This can be quite useful for activating interactors.

## Automated Machines

A variety of machines can be automated by installing an [bold]Automation Upgrade[/bold] on them.

This can unlock:
- signal ports to control the machine by linking it to buttons, logic gates, etc.
- signal ports that get invoked when the machine does something.
- item automation storage ports for the [bold]robotic arm[/bold] to use.
- item filter slots
- and others

Here is every machine that accepts automation upgrades:

<GuideAutomationSlotsEmbed/>

Note that currently, only some machines can be activated with a signal - for example the Flatpacker can be activated to automatically flatpack materials. However the techfabs and lathes still require manual input.

## Storage Bin

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StorageBin"/>

The Storage Bin is a large storage space that can be accessed by robotic arms by default, without the need for an automation upgrade (unlike a disposals bin, for example).

It has a filter slot to control what items can be inserted, similar to a robotic arm.

A good use of a storage bin is stacking up items within it and then extracting them in chunks using a stack filter robotic arm.

## Interactor

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Interactor"/>

This device simulates left click interactions with its held item on an entity infront of it.
If no item is held it's like pressing E, such as opening a door/crate, picking up an item, etc.

It stores its tool in an actual hand so you can swap it out with the strip menu by pressing E on it.

Its filter slot is used to change what entities it will interact with. Using a proper filter is essential as it will only try to interact with 1 item at a time.
It will search for [bold]any entity[/bold] without a filter, even things like conveyors or puddles! Use filters.

It has 5 signal ports:
Input:
- Start, used to try interacting with something
- Auto Start, which when enabled will automatically try to interact after a successful interaction. If no interaction happens, it will automatically deactivate.
Output:
- Started, invoked if the interaction starts an interaction
- Completed, invoked on interaction succeeds OR when the interaction ends
- Failed, invoked if it could not interact with anything

## Constructor

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Constructor"/>

This machine will construct or craft new objects like you would in the construction menu. Click it to open an UI to select which thing to craft.
The machine will only complete the first step, [bold]use interactors to finish multi-step constructions[/bold].
Construction ghosts and created items both get placed infront of it. The machine can be rotated, which will change where crafted items and built structures are placed.

Input items are taken from the floor nearby as well as its internal storage, which doubles as a storage bin.

It has the same ports as an Interactor.

## Filters

Filters can be inserted into robotic arms and storage bins to restrict what items they can move and store respectively.

You can craft them by hand using the [bold]construction menu[/bold]. Left click them into machines to insert them.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterName"/>
The name filter searches an item's name in some way.
For example, if you set it to check that an item [italic]contains[/italic] "sheet", it will match steel sheets, glass sheets, etc.
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterLabel"/>
The label filter requires items to have an exact matching label.
Use a hand labeler on items to have them picked up.
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterStack"/>
The stack filter controls how it interacts with stacks.
The minimum stack size is a simple minimum, if an item doesn't have that much in a stack it won't be used.
Out chunk size limits how many of a stack can be taken. Only a whole multiple of this size will be taken out.
[italic]For example, a chunk size of 5 on stacks of 6, 10, 14 and 15 will take 5, 10, 10 and 15 respectively.[/italic]
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterCombined"/>
The combined filter stores 2 filters inside it and uses a logic gate to control how they function.
By default it will allow any item that passes either filter (an OR gate).
It supports all the same operations that logic gate items do.
These can be nested for arbitrarily complex filters!
</Box>

## Transport

Conveyor belts are an obvious way to transport items around as they allow machines to pick up from them.

In the future, you wil also be able to use automated disposal units to flush items around.

You can also use a chain or robotic arms for transportation, but this is power inefficient.

## Radiation Collector and gas canister ports

Both the radiator collector and gas canisters can be also upgraded with an automation upgrade kit. This will allow to automate insertion and extraction of gas tanks and add a series of signal ports.

Upon applying the automation upgrade gas canisters will gain a series of signal ports:

Input:
- Open - opens the gas release valve
- Close - closes the release valve
- Toggle - toggles the state of the release valve


With an upgrade, the radiation collector will gain the following signal ports:

Output:
- RadEmpty - sets signal to HIGH if the gas tank is either missing or below 33% pressure. Otherwise, outputs a LOW signal.
- RadLow - sets signal to HIGH if the gas tank is below 66% pressure. Otherwise, outputs a LOW signal.
- RadHigh- sets signal to HIGH if the gas tank is above 66% pressure. Otherwise, outputs a LOW signal.

You can use an Edge Detector (crafted in the construction menu) to differentiate between a HIGH and LOW signals.

</Document>
