<Document>
# Medical Doctor
"Medicine, the advanced technology of today."

The medical department is the backbone of keeping crew alive, wether that be a missing arm, bodies burnt to a crisp, severe lacerations...It's up to you to fix their oopsies and boo-boos!

This guide states the basic outline of the treatment options and other avenues of care that you can take as a doctor.

## The Basics

When you first recieve a patient, you first need to know what's wrong with them! There are two ways of doing this.

- [bold]By doing a basic health inspection[/bold]. You can do this by hovering over a patient and using [color=yellow][keybind="ExamineEntity"][/color] and clicking the heart icon. It will show you any 'obvious' wounds, like bruising, blood loss and burns. But will not show things like poison!
- [bold]Using a health analyzer[/bold]. All medical PDA's comes with [color=#4ba9bc]Medtek[/color], a health analyzer program. The health analyzer allows you to view [bold]all damage[/bold] that a patient has recieved, including their [bold]blood level[/bold]. Along with a coloured figure that shows if any body parts are damaged.

To use a health analyzer, hold your PDA (or Handheld Health Analyzer) and then press [color=yellow][keybind="Use"][/color] when hovering over a patient.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalPDA"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalInternPDA" Caption="intern PDA"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldHealthAnalyzer" Caption="Handheld Health Analyzer"/>
</Box>

It is important to note that the [bold]Handheld Health Analyzer[/bold] [italic]is the only one that requires a power cell[/italic]. Only use this if you do not have [color=#4ba9bc]Medtek[/color], or your PDA!

## Common Damage Types and basic treatments

The damage types [bold]all affect the patients health the same way.[/bold] The only thing different is that all of them require a different treatment to heal.

Doctors come equipped with a [bold]medical belt[/bold] that contains medical tools to deal with the most common types of damages. These are called [color=orange]Topicals.[/color]


<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyMedipen"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bloodpack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze"/>
</Box>

- [bold]Brutepacks[/bold] are for all types of Brute. This includes; slash, piercing, and bruises.
- [bold]Ointments[/bold] are for all types of Burns. This includes eletrical shocks, heat and caustic.
- [bold]Gauze[/bold] is to stop bleeding on a patient, it also works for slash and piercing!
- [bold]Bloodpacks[/bold] is to refill a patients blood. This bloodpack works for every species. The patient will be pale if they require blood!
- [bold]Emergency Medipens[/bold] are for when the patient is exceptionally close to deaths door. [bold]It will heal them from most types of damage while they are in critical condition[/bold] and buy you more time for life saving treatment!

These are the most common type of damages that you can expect to see within all patients that arrive in medbay.
If you ever run out these, you may refill your medical belt from medkits!

### Medkits

Many stations are stocked with medkits in medbay, and are a great source to restock if your medical belt runs dry on resources.
Medkits can also be for specific damage types, be sure to read your [bold]Health Analyzer[/bold] for which medkit to use!

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitFilled"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitBruteFilled" Caption="brute kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitRadiationFilled" Caption="radiation kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitBurnFilled" Caption="burn kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitToxinFilled" Caption="toxin kit"/>
</Box>

If your department is running low on medkits, ask your [color=#b18644]Logistics Department[/color] for a restock!


## Advanced Damage Types and chemicals

Although you are equipped to deal with the most common types of damage, you do not come equipped to deal with [italic]all[/italic] damage types by default.

For that, [bold]you need to utilise chemicals![/bold]
Chemicals are way more effective than the tools on your medical belt, and can treat more types of damage.

To get started, find yourself a jet injector or syringe.
<Box>

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="JetInjector"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SyringeBluespace"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Hypospray"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Jug" Caption="Chem container"/>
</Box>
Jet injectors are the medical tool you will be likely using the most. They can be found in lockers or the NanoMed Plus. You can click on a jug of medicine with a jet injector and it will draw 5 units from the jug at a time. You can draw however much you need, then click on someone with the jet injector and it will automatically inject all of the medicine you've put into the jet injector into the patient.

Syringes have two modes, [bold]Draw[/bold] and [bold]Inject[/bold]. They are a bit more cumbersome to use than jet injectors, but they can draw blood or other chemicals from things that jet injectors cannot.
- When you press [color=yellow][keybind="Use"][/color] while hovering over a chemical container in [bold]Draw[/bold] mode, it will gather chemicals from that container.
- Then it will switch to [bold]Inject[/bold] mode. When you press [color=yellow][keybind="Use"][/color] while hovering over a patient, it will inject that chemical into their bloodstream. Then switches back to [bold]Draw[/bold] mode.

You may also request for the chemicals to be in pill form if you wish.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PillCanister"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Pill" Caption="Any pill"/>
</Box>

But before you even start injecting chemicals into patients, you have to understand some important things.
- Most chemicals have something called an "[color=red]Overdose rate[/color]". Overdose happens when the patients body has been injected with too many [italic]units[/italic] of that medicine. [bold]This can harm or kill the patient![/bold]
- Your [textlink="Chemist" link="Chemist"] will be where you get your medicine from. Be sure to also ask them to [bold]label their chems[/bold]; as this will save you from having to memorise what medicine does what, especially their [color=red]Overdose rate[/color].
- All chemicals are measured in [italic]units[/italic], as they are considered a liquid.
- Chitnids can not be injected with normal syringes. [bold]Use a hypospray or pills.[/bold]

With that out of the way, you are now free to inject chemicals into patients to save lives!

If you wish to see how to make chemicals (because there is not a chemist), you may look at the common chemical recipes [textlink="here." link="FrequentlyUsedChemicals"]

## How to assess patients
As a doctor. You may be under quite a heavy workload, now that you know how to inject chemicals and use topicals.
However, it generally follows this order:

- First, once you recieve a patient, lay them on a [bold]medical bed[/bold]. Only use a [bold]stasis bed[/bold] if the patients death is imminent (or has died already).
- Secondly, scan the patient with a health analyzer to check their damages.
- Third, inject the patient with the correct chemical, or use Topicals to start treatment.
- Fourth, discharge the patient once you confirm they are fully treated of their wounds.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBed"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StasisBed"/>
</Box>

## Reviving dead patients
Unfortunatley, there is some cases where death comes to a patient faster than you can react. However, this is not the end of the world!

The revival procedure uses a Defibrillator to restart the patients heart. But you need to do these things first:

- Check if the patient has [bold]rotted[/bold]. You can not revive a rotting patient, and must morgue them.
- If not rotting, put them on a [bold]stasis bed[/bold] to prevent further decomposition!
- [bold]Get their current damage underneath 200.[/bold] You [color=orange]cannot use chems on the dead[/color] as it wont metabolise.
- Once under 200 damage. Get your defibrillator from the cabinet, press [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ActivateItemInHand"][/bold][/color] to turn the defibrillator on in your main hand, and shout "Clear!"
- Drag the patient off the [bold]stasis bed[/bold]. As chemicals metabolise slowly on cold temperatures. Then continue treatment as normal.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Defibrillator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DefibrillatorCabinetFilled" Caption="Defib cabinet"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment"/>
</Box>

[color=yellow]Keep in mind that the defibrillator recharges while it is in its cabinet![/color]

### Rotting patients
Patients that are rotting arent a lost cause! As [textlink="Cloning" link="Cloning"] or [textlink="Cryogenics" link="Cryogenics"] are an option if you have them.

### Unique Patients
- Some patients are unique! Some may have a [color=yellow]unique body composition![/color] This means [bold]they can't be cloned or revived by defibrillators.[/bold] Ask your [textlink="Surgeon" link="Surgery"] for help about brain transplants.

- Some patients [italic]might die at 100 damage [/italic]instead of having a critical state! Get them down to under 100 damage and do the revival procedure as usual.
</Document>
