<Document>
  # Hitman

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"Mission Started."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>

    You're an [color=yellow]Criminal[/color], who takes money to kill people. [color=cyan]Your client wants you to kill them in a very perticuler way.[/color] pay attention to your conditions.

    ##Teach your target a lesson
    Your client wants that your client dies once [color=red][italic]by your hand following their specifications.[/italic][/color]
    - [bold]They need not stay dead. Your client only cares that they die once, not for how long they are dead.[/bold]
    - [bold]This is your one task, take the time needed to plan it out.[/bold]


    ##Kill the target brutaly
    Your client wants your target to die in some way which would mental scar those who saw it.
    - [bold]This doesnt mean you have to burn them into ash or otherwise destroy their body.[/bold] burning them to death or filling them with knife wounds can work.
    - Almost all of the methods to furfill this are very loud and overt. Either prepare a exit plan or do it far away from any witnesses.

    ##Kill the target dramaticly
    Your client wants to make this murder dramatic in a story telling sense.
    - You may need to interact with your target socially to set up the correct narrative tension, but remember you need a reason to be talking with them to not seem suspicious.
    - The best tragedies involve a fault of their victims. Knowing what kind of person your target is could help.

    ##Kill the target humorously
    Your client wants to make your targets death a joke.
    - Absurb methods of death are funny. Look into what doesnt seem like it could kill but can.
    - The station and clown has a lot of silly items. Searching maintenance tunnels and the clowns room may get you something usefull.

    ##Kill the target cleanly
    Your client doesnt want the targets death to make a mess or otherwise look bad.
    - Any forms of damage which are Internal will be very usefull here.
    - If one must use more usaul means to finish the kill, reparing the body can stop it from becoming a mess.

    ##Make your targets death look like a accident.
    Your client wants your targets death to not look like a murder.
    - Using or faking regular dangers in their department can go a long way towards making people believe you.
    - If the body does not get reported as suspicious then its unlikely anyone will guestion it further.

    ##Kill your target indirectly.
    Your client doesnt want you anywhere near the body once it drops. They want you to find a remote way of killing them.
    - The remote signaler can be very usefull for setting up traps or timing kills.
    - Having a method to tell your targets location will likely be very usefull in telling when a trap need be sprung.

    ##Drag out your targets death.
    Your client wants your target to suffer. They ask to make their death take a long one.
    - Healing supplies could be usefull in ensuring they survive longer than usual.
    - By the nature of this, you likely want to make your method quiet or kill them in a place no one will look for them.

    ##Kill your target in a public space.
    Your client wants to send a message by having them die where everyone will see.
    - Having a method to hide your idenity will be very useful when you need to do this in front of witnesses.
    - Using something to cause panic can be useful in giving you an opening.

    ##Inform your target they are a target.
    Your client wants you to inform the target they will be assassinated [color=red][bold]long before it happens.[/bold][/color]
    - Doing this will almost always put you under suspicion. Find a method to hide your identity or inform them indirectly.
    - Doing this early on could make your target grow compliant.

    ##Kill someone close to your target and make sure they know.
    Your client wants to mentally harm your target by killing someone close to them.
    - The person you kill has to be found out to be dead by your target. This can not be a silent or permanent kill.
    - You'll need to interact with and stalk your target to figure out who is close to them.
    - Theres no modifers on killing the person close to them.
</Document>
