<Document>
  # Internal Affairs Agent

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"CENTRAL COMMAND EMPLOYEE PROMOTION TO INTERNAL SECURITY HAS BEEN PROCESSED."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"ALL DAMAGES WILL BE SUBTRACTED FROM YOUR ACCOUNTS."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"STAND BY FOR ORDERS."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterLegitNanotrasenLogo" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  You're an agent for [color=#204cc7]NanoTrasen[/color], sent here to do some dirty work for them. [color=cyan]The only thing your employers ask of you, is to limit your damage to other employees or company property.[/color] Otherwise, you're going to be billed for it.

  [color=red]Remember, no one likes a snitch,[/color] so revealing yourself to others that you work for the Big Man won't do you any favors. Keep your agenda hidden.

  ##The Singular Gadget
  Unfortunately, due to budget cuts, your employers didn't really give you access to fancy tools, [bold]except for your radio implanter.[/bold]

  You might have another agent active, which you can easily communicate with by using your radio with [color=cyan]y:[/color]

  You could also contact your [bold]handler[/bold], which is [color=green]Central Command[/color]. They might give you a hand on some things, but don't rely on it.

  ##Getting Someone Fired
  [italic]A certain Employee might've gotten too comfortable with their position, which could potentially spell bad news for NanoTrasen. Have them explore other job opportunities.[/italic]

  Getting someone fired might be easy or difficult, depending on their job. If a janitor, it should be easy, but if it's a Command member, it might be harder (especially the Captain.).

  However, making up a reason shouldn't be too hard. Writing a "credible" report about their breach of [textlink="The Company Policy" link="companyPolicies"] or their behaviour might help you if you spy on them. Otherwise, putting them in a bad spot that you've made up might do the trick too. Convincing them to wear Syndicate clothing would make their bosses [italic]very happy![/italic]

  ##Getting Someone Framed
  [italic]Someone got on NanoTrasen's bad side. They need you to ensure they end up in prison.[/italic]

  Framing someone sounds harder than it looks, especially when you don't have easy access to contraband. Though your ingenuity might come in handy. [color=cyan]Remember, they need to end up in prison at Midpoint.[/color]
  - [bold]Spy on your target, watch for any opportunities or moments where they commit something illegal, or make them commit something.[/bold] Maybe a clown is willing to pick a fight with them, so you can falsely report the target of starting the fight?
  - [bold]Use the environment to your advantage.[/bold] Was there sabotage or an explosion going off? You better inform the Security Officer about a [italic]certain suspicious individual you saw.[/italic]

  Remember, security is usually dumber (or smarter) than they seem. They might be too busy with their jobs to remember your face, but they might remember your small clue. Hell, you could become the Detective's best informant. Just try not to overdo it. Station might wisen up to your antics. [italic]You need to SELL your lie effectively![/italic]

  ##Auditing a Department
  [italic]NanoTrasen needs you to check how their valued departments work.[/italic]

  Auditing a department is a very open-minded objective. How it's done, how much is done is entirely up to you, [bold]but Central Command needs that report from you.[/bold]

  - Inspect your chosen Department! You might find certain infractions or SOP breaches.
  - Test the reaction time of the Department. Breaking into bridge and seeing how fast Security can escort you out will work. Cutting power from Logistics, just to see how long it takes for Engineering to figure out the problem also helps.

  You're the auditor! Figure out what's MOST important to audit.

  ##Defunding a Department
  [italic]NanoTrasen needs a good reason why overfunding certain departments is a bad idea.[/italic]

  Your job is to pick a Department of your choosing and ensure that their Department Budget is almost all empty by the end of the shift.

  You can either secretly pocket all of the money or waste their funds on entirely useless things. If they don't have the cash, you can also ensure that the department starts lacking certain things, like chairs or even consoles!

  - Withdrawing cash from the ordering console usually leaves a big radio announcement of who done it. Limit your withdrawls or use someone else's ID to take it.
  - People are going to notice if certain important objects go missing from their departments, which can arouse unwanted attention. Start small and go from there. Use distractions to your advantage and try to get things unnoticed.

  ##Getting Called by Your Handler
  From time to time, you might get a small request from [color=green]Central Command Officials[/color] to do some extra work. While it's [italic]not mandatory[/italic] to complete them, they might be willing to help you out later if you help them out.

  However, if you're [italic]looking[/italic] for extra work, contacting your superiors is always an option!
</Document>
