<Document>
# Medical Doctor
"Medicine, the advanced technology of today."

The medical department is the backbone of keeping crew alive, wether that be a missing arm, bodies burnt to a crisp, severe lacerations...It's up to you to fix their oopsies and boo-boos!

This guide states the basic outline of the treatment options and other avenues of care that you can take as a doctor.

## The Basics

When you first recieve a patient, you first need to know what's wrong with them! There are two ways of doing this.

- [bold]Using a health analyzer[/bold]. The health analyzer allows you to view [bold]all damage[/bold] that a patient has recieved, including their [bold]blood level[/bold]. Along with a coloured figure showing which part of their body is the most damaged. The health analyzer also categorises damages into their own categories for convenience.

- [bold]By doing a basic health inspection[/bold]. You can do this by using [color=yellow][keybind="ExamineEntity"][/color] and clicking the heart icon. It will show you any 'obvious' wounds, like bruising, blood loss and burns. But will not show things like poison!
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalPDA"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalInternPDA" Caption="intern PDA"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldHealthAnalyzer" Caption="Handheld Health Analyzer"/>
</Box>

It is important to note that the [bold]Handheld Health Analyzer[/bold] [italic]is the only one that requires a power cell[/italic].

## Common Damage Types and basic treatments

The damage types [bold]all affect the patients health the same way.[/bold] The only thing different is that all of them require a different treatment to heal.

Doctors come equipped with a [bold]medical belt[/bold] that contains medical tools to deal with the most common types of damages.


<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyMedipen"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bloodpack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze"/>
</Box>

- [bold]Brutepacks[/bold] are for all types of Brute. This includes; slash, piercing, and bruises.
- [bold]Ointments[/bold] are for all types of Burns. This includes eletrical shocks, heat and caustic.
- [bold]Gauze[/bold] is to stop bleeding on a patient, it also works for slash and piercing!
- [bold]Bloodpacks[/bold] is to refill a patients blood. This bloodpack works for every species. The patient will be pale if they require blood!
- [bold]Emergency Medipens[/bold] are for when the patient is exceptionally close to deaths door. [bold]It will heal them from most types of damage while they are in critical condition[/bold] and buy you more time for life saving treatment!

These are the most common type of damages that you can expect to see within all patients that arrive in medbay.
If you ever run out these, you may refill your medical belt from medkits!

### Medkits

Many stations are stocked with medkits in medbay, and are a great source to restock if your medical belt runs dry on resources.
Medkits can also be for specific damage types, be sure to read your [bold]Health Analyzer[/bold] for which medkit to use!

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitFilled"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitBruteFilled" Caption="brute kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitRadiationFilled" Caption="radiation kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitBurnFilled" Caption="burn kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitToxinFilled" Caption="toxin kit"/>
</Box>

If your department is running low on medkits, ask your [color=#b18644]Logistics Department[/color] for a restock!


## Advanced Damage Types and medicine

Although you are equipped to deal with the most common types of damage, you do not come equipped to deal with [italic]all[/italic] damage types by default.

For that, you need to utilise medicine!

Medicine is way more effective than the tools on your medical belt, and can treat more types of damage.




- Brute Damage: [color=#ffaa00]Bicaridine[/color], Bruise Packs or Medicated Sutures.
- Burn Damage: [color=#215263]Dermaline[/color], Ointment or Regenerative Meshes.
- Toxin (Poison): [color=#6756c9]Dylovene[/color]
- Toxin (Radiation) [color=#4cb580]Hyronalin[/color] or [color=#bd5902]Arithrazine.[/color]
- Airloss: [color=#0041a8]Dexalin[/color], [color=#639cc7]Salbutamol[/color], [color=#731024]Inaprovaline[/color], or [color=#e80d7e]Convermol.[/color]
- Blood loss: [color=#0041a8]Dexalin[/color] or [color=#639cc7]Salbutamol[/color] (Examine the patient; if pale, they still need blood or iron.)
- Bleeding: [color=#ba7d7d]Tranexamic acid[/color], Gauze or Medicated Sutures. (Bleeding can also be cauterised with burn damage.)



## Basic Treatment and Triage
Examine your patient, and note down the important details: Are they alive? Bleeding? What type of damage?

If alive, treat them as best as you can. Patients are in critical condition at 100 damage, [bold]unless they have the redshirt trait[/bold]; but at most, those without redshirt will die at 200 damage. Keep this in mind when choosing how to treat them. Emergency Pens and [color=#c0f5f9]Epinephrine[/color] are often used to stabilise patients. However, you may also do [color=#e84037]CPR[/color] to stabilise them.

If possible, buckle them to a medical bed; if you need time to treat them, strap them to a stasis bed instead. Just keep in mind that metabolism (and by extension, the production of healing chemicals) is slowed to a crawl when on stasis; it'll need to be taken off of it for the medicine to be effective. (But Blood Packs, Ointment, and Brute packs all work as normal.)
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBed"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StasisBed"/>
</Box>
## Assessing Corpses
You can't save them all; sometimes, death happens. Depending on the status of the body, follow this checklist:

- First, check if they have a soul attached. Their soul is attached to their brain, and by extension their head. If they are decapitated, it will always say "[color=#653b89]Their soul has departed and moved on.[/color]" upon examination...But dont let that fool you, they could still have their soul very much there! Reattach their head via [textlink="Surgery" link="Surgery"]. Then you can recheck to see if they are truly gone.

- Secondly, now check to see if they have a [bold]unique body composition[/bold]. You can tell if your health scanner says "[color=yellow]Unique body composition detected![/color]". If this happens, it means that their Brain will need to be transplanted into a body donor via [textlink="Surgery" link="Surgery"].
(IPCs/Borgs are a possible body donor if a patients Brain is compatible with MMI technology. A patients brain WILL NOT be compatible if it says this on your health scanner: "[color=red]Patients' brain signatures are incompatible with MMI[/color]".)

- [bold]If they do not have a unique body composition;[/bold] check to see if their body is rotting. If it is, you will have to get your hands on a rot-healing cryogenic chemical, such as [color=#b5e36d]Opporozidone[/color] or [color=#e3d56d]Netinadone[/color]. A rotting body can't be brought back unless you fix its rot, [textlink="cloning" link="Cloning"] is an alternative if you don't have cryogenic chemicals at your disposal.

- And finally, with their soul in their body, their body being fresh, and a [bold]normal body composition[/bold], proceed to reviving the patient.

## Reviving
The revival procedure uses a Defibrillator to restart the patients heart. The Defibrillator can be used to revive patients with aspyhxiation damage, but will deal [bold]5 shock damage[/bold]. Patients need to be under 200 damage in order to be revived with a defib (or under 100 with redshirt). Chemicals don't metabolise in the dead, but brute packs and ointment can still patch them up. Use them to bring their numbers down enough for revival.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Defibrillator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DefibrillatorCabinetFilled" Caption="Defib cabinet"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment"/>
</Box>

[color=yellow]Keep in mind that the defibrillator recharges while it is in its cabinet![/color]
</Document>

