<Document>
  # Hearings
  NanoTrasen authorizes its Justice Department to conduct Hearings in order to determine if a person accused of sufficient crimes may be held in indefinite custody, to be handed over to GalPol at the end of the shift. The purpose of these hearings is not to determine legally binding guilt, but to measure how feasible their guilt is; and to avoid lawsuits which would tarnish the NanoTrasen brand.

  Hearings are a tool of Space Law. Like any other action that represents the Law, they are subject to Procedural Defense as detailed in Space Law.

  A hearing must be held for capital charges, and for sentences that exceed a total of 25 minutes when added together. The right for a hearing may be waived by the suspect by pleading guilty, under martial law, or in absence of any Justice personnel on station.

  A hearing is conducted by a Judge (chosen in order from: Chief Justice, Clerk, Commanding Officer, Command), who charged is with ensuring the hearing is completed, decides the time and location of the hearing, and whether they want to make the hearing accessible to the public or not. A hearing must include the Judge and Prosecution, and should additionally include the accused and defense, if available. The Judge has the right to find any person in the hearing guilty of contempt of court. Hearings are concerned with any and all crimes the accused is currently charged with, not just capital crimes.

  Defense must be provided to the accused if requested and feasible, and should consist of either an attorney, any member of the justice department, or any sophont chosen by the accused. The prosecution should consist of either a prosecutor, any member of the justice department, or any member of station security.

  Neither prosecution nor defense may interrupt one another during presentation of evidence, including objecting to witness statements made. In the case of a witness making demonstrably untrue statements, perjury and contempt of court may be charged as necessary. It is encouraged the judge pay attention and inquire about competing claims to truth.
</Document>
