  <Document>
# Server Rules
  This is a NovaSector server. You must be at least 18 years of age to play on this server.

  [color=#ffDD00]This is a high roleplaying (HRP) server. Immerse yourself into your character. Interact with your fellow crewmates, and use roleplay as the primary vessel to play the game. Roleplaying places less emphasis on "winning" and more on telling a story together.[/color]

  Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play. Game admins will treat you as if you have read the rules, even if you have not. If you have any questions about these rules, please use the admin help menu by hitting F1 in-game or clicking the "AHelp" button in the lobby.

  ## Community Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  - [textlink="0. Admins can exercise discretion in the enforcement of rules." link="NovaRule0"]
  - [textlink="A1. Do not say or do sexually explicit or erotic things." link="NovaRuleA1"]
  - [textlink="A2. Use English and be respectful." link="NovaRuleA2"]
  - [textlink="A3. Follow the rules regarding livestreaming current rounds." link="NovaRuleA3"]
  - [textlink="A4. Engage in proper AHelp etiquette." link="NovaRuleA4"]
  - [textlink="A5. Do not exploit the game." link="NovaRuleA5"]

  ## Game Server Rules
  These rules apply within the context of rounds.
  - [textlink="B1. Behave like a normal person." link="NovaRule1"]
  - [textlink="B2. Follow the Metashield." link="NovaRule2"]
  - [textlink="B3. Do not prioritize winning over roleplay." link="NovaRule3"]
  - [textlink="B4. Do not behave like an antagonist as a non-antagonist." link="NovaRule4"]
  - [textlink="B5. Leave the game using cryosleep." link="NovaRule5"]

  ## Command, Security, and Antagonist Guidelines
  These rules apply within rounds for specific roles.
  - [textlink="C1. Command and Security Guidelines" link="NovaRuleC1"]
  - [textlink="C2. Prisoner Guidelines." link="NovaRuleC2"]
  - [textlink="C3. Follow Antagonist Guidelines" link="NovaRuleC3"]

  ## Silicon Rules
  For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules. You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon.
  - [textlink="S1. Your silicon laws are rules" link="NovaRuleS1"]
  - [textlink="S2. Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="NovaRuleS2"]
  - [textlink="S3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="NovaRuleS3"]
  - [textlink="S4. You cannot request or allow a law change" link="NovaRuleS4"]
  - [textlink="S5. You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="NovaRuleS5"]
  - [textlink="S6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="NovaRuleS6"]
  - [textlink="S7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="NovaRuleS7"]
  - [textlink="S8. Crew are staff members; make reasonable assumptions" link="NovaRuleS8"]
  - [textlink="S9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="NovaRuleS9"]
  - [textlink="S10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="NovaRuleS10"]
</Document>
