<Document>
  # Rule C1: Command, Security and Justice Guidelines
Security, Justice, and Command roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay, and are subject to these additional rules. These roles shape the roleplay experience of the server. 
  - Your character must act in a manner that NanoTrasen would reasonably hire them to this position.
    - Your character is presumed to be sane, competent in their duties, and able to make decisions to the benefit of the station. 
    - Giving away Traitor objective items and sensitive equipment should be avoided in these roles. Your character should value them deeply. 
      - Leeway is given to making deals with criminals if the deal benefits the safety or situation of the crew and station OR if the deal involves items of a primarily sentimental value (e.g. HoP's Ian scrapbook, LO's lucky dollar).
      - Leeway can be given in [color=#ff0000]extreme circumstances[/color] of emergency/crisis.
  - The three departments are required to read and follow Delta-V Space Law, Standard Operating Procedure, Alert Procedure, and Company Policy to the best of their ability.
    - [color=#ff0000]Circumstances and context may permit you to break these laws. However, the fact that this rule is malleable is not an excuse to ignore it entirely.[/color]
    - Your character is expected to uphold the law and maintain order aboard the station. Do not engage in lawbreaking activity or troublemaker behavior, and ensure all laws are followed.
    - Security is expected to intervene in criminal activity where possible and safe to do so. 
    - Heads of departments are at minimum expected to report criminal activity to Security and should cooperate with law enforcement where possible.
  - Do not hire random crew to be your bodyguard(s) or promote random crewmembers to Command positions at random. If you require bodyguards or security details, talk to your Security department. If you need new Command staff, talk to the personnel in that related department.
  - If you need to leave the round, notify your fellow crew via departmental radio and put your equipment in its proper places prior to going to cryo. If you need to leave IMMEDIATELY, please at least send an ahelp saying that you're leaving.
</Document>
