<Document>
  # Rule C1: Command, Security and Justice Guidelines
  - Security, Justice, and Command roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay, and are expected to know and perform their jobs to the best of their ability. These roles often heavily impact the round and require more careful and conscientious roleplay; if you cannot meet these requirements do not take these roles.
    - The three departments are required to read and follow Delta-V Space Law, Standard Operating Procedure, Alert Procedure, and Company Policy to the best of their ability.
    - Abandoning your role to go do whatever you want instead of managing your department or maintaining security, abusing your position or using it to make arbitrary or malicious choices to the detriment of the station, and being negligent to the point of harm is prohibited.
  - If you need to leave the round, notify your fellow crew via departmental radio and put your equipment in its proper places prior to going to cryo. If you need to leave IMMEDIATELY, please at least send an ahelp saying that you're leaving.
  - Do not give up or trade away Traitor objective items, departmental/Command tools and remotes, and sensitive equipment without excellent reason.
    - Some leeway is given to making deals with criminals [italic]if and only if[/italic] the deal benefits the safety or situation of the station or circumstances rather than just yourself (e.g. hostage situations).
    - Some leeway can be given in [color=#ff0000]extreme circumstances[/color] of extreme shortstaffing and/or emergency/crisis.
  - Command, Justice, and Security are expected to uphold the law and maintain order aboard the station. Do not engage in lawbreaking activity or troublemaker behavior, and ensure that company policy and standard operating procedure - not just space law - is being observed. Security is expected to intervene into criminal activity where possible and safe to do so. Heads of departments are at minimum expected to report criminal activity to Security and should cooperate with law enforcement where possible.
  - Do not hire random crew to be your bodyguard(s) or promote random crewmembers to Command positions at random. If you require bodyguards or security details, talk to your Security department. If you need new Command staff, talk to the personnel in that related department.

</Document>