<Document>
  # Treatment of Prisoners
  Prisoners have certain rights that must be upheld by law enforcement and Station Command. Prisoners must be provided with the following:

  - Adequate medical care and moral, spiritual, or legal counseling if it is requested and available.
  - Access to the Common and Prison radio channels only while serving their sentence. This right may be revoked should it be abused.
  - Standard prisoner clothing must always be available for prisoners.
  - Confiscated clothing should be returned upon request, except in the case of Extended Confinement or if the clothing in question poses a clear risk to prisoner or crew safety.
  - Food and water for organic prisoners must be available and given on request.
  - Power for silicon prisoners such as IPCs and cyborgs, at minimum a cyborg recharging station must be provided.
  - Should the holding cells or Permabrig become uninhabitable, prisoners must be securely and safely relocated to another area for confinement, until the holding cells or Permabrig are returned to a serviceable state.
  - Prisoners should be granted freedom of movement within their holding area unless there is an undue risk to life and limb.

  Additionally, prisoners sentenced to Extended Confinement have certain rights but also [bold]more firm restrictions that must be upheld by law enforcement[/bold]:

  - Visitation may be permitted only for prisoners sentenced to Extended Confinement. A reason must be provided for the visit, and the visitor must consent to a search of their belongings.
  - Prisoners may request an appeal for capital crimes; these requests may be refused depending on the discretion and availability of the Clerk, Chief Justice, or at the discretion of the warden or head of station security.
  - Prisoners may request or may otherwise be given parole by the Warden or Head of Security.
  - Should prisoners repeatedly and maliciously antagonize law enforcement, to an extent where continued extended confinement becomes infeasible, the warden is fully authorized and encouraged to upgrade the relevant prisoners’ sentences to Exfiltration summarily.

  Moreover, prisoners are liable for any and all crimes that they commit while held either in the temporary holding cells or the Permanent Brig, and may, in the case of the Permanent Brig, be placed in solitary confinement for the duration of the sentence the committed crimes incur.
</Document>
